Inventory of the Thomas H. (Thomas Hawkins) Johnson Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Carnegie Mellon University (CMU), 1987-1989 (Folder 47: 16)
  Agenda, letters, list of students pursuing a Ph.D. in the Engineering and Public Safety Department, newsletters, outlines, and miscellany
- Roy Alcala committee, 1989 (Folder 47: 17)
  Agenda and briefings, letter, and memorandum
- Search for the position of Head of Systems Engineering, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York, 1988-1989 (Folder 47: 18)
  Course outline, curriculum vitae, letter, list of professors and head of the Civil and Mechanical Engineering Department, memoranda, and notes
- United Nations Institute for Disarmament Research (UNIDIR) expert group meeting on "Problems of Definition and Demarcation in the Prevention of an Arms Race in Outer Space," Sochi, USSR, 1988 October 19-20 (Folder 47: 19)
  Brochure, letters, list of experts, minutes of meeting, and telegram
- Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) Inertial Fusion Advisory Committee (IFAC), 1987-1988 (Folder 47: 20)
  Article, letters, list of committee members, and memoranda
- Nuclear power study, 1987-1988 (Folder 47: 21)
  Articles, notes, statement, and related information. Also includes agenda, biographies of speakers, and list of participants for the Colloquium on "Nuclear Operations and Command and Control," Center for Public Policy Education, Brookings Institution, Washington, D.C., 1987 March 9
- National Research Council (NRC) space study, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  Agenda for a meeting, financial record relating to travel, letters, list of members of the technology assessment committee, memoranda, notes, organizational chart, progress report, and related materials. Also includes a letter confirming Thomas Johnson's appointment as a member of the Technology Assessment Committee to the U.S. Space Command of the Air Force Studies Board, Commission on Engineering and Technical Systems
- Army Space Master Plan project, 1985 (Folder 48: 2)
  Agenda, letters, list of names of attendees and their travel schedule, newsletter, notes, outline and related materials
- Trans World Airlines (TWA), 1987 (Folder 48: 3)
  Brochures and newsletters relating to frequent flight program
- Army Science Board, 1985-1988 (Folder 48: 4)
  Agenda for Army Science Board Ballistic Missile Defense (BMD) Program panel meeting, article, letters, list of participants, memoranda, and outline, and miscellany
- Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL), 1983-1989 (Folder 48: 5)
  Consultant agreement for Thomas Johnson's services and related materials
- DCSRDA research initiative, 1985-1986 (Folder 48: 6)
  Disposition form, letters, memoranda, notes, and proposal
- Items of interest, 1983 (Folder 48: 7)
  Memoranda relating to Thomas Johnson's activities as Assistant Dean for Academic Research and Director, Science Research Laboratory, United States Military Academy
- Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI), 1986-1987 (Folder 48: 8)
  Letters, program, notes, and related materials. Includes an article by Thomas Johnson, "Technologies of Ballistic Missile Defense and the ABM Treaty," undated
- Stanford Center for International Security and Arms Control, 1984-1988 (Folder 48: 9)
  Annual report, brochure, letters, newsletter, and program
- Articles relating to ICF tritium production reactor, free electron reactors, laser driver for an ICF reactor, effects of atmospheric wind profiles on propagation, 1985-1989 (Box 49)
  Includes articles in Russian
- Comments on glass laser driver, T. Coffey, undated
- Foreign Affairs, 1988 summer
- List of names of Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory Inertial Confinement Fusion advisory committee members, undated
- Notes and miscellany regarding Athena design, laser technology, and other related matters, undated
- "Theory of Optical Guiding in a Free Electron Lasers," Ming Xie, 1988 summer
- Reports and annual reports, 1988-1989
  Includes Department of Defense annual reports to the Congress
- Reports relating to atmospheric turbulence, beam research program, national airspace system plan, and other related subjects, 1981-1988 (Box 50)
  Also includes Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Inc. annual awards presentation program
- Reports on air traffic control system, axisymmetric and mirror plasma, conceptual design of an auto-resonant accelerator experiment, fusion and hose theory, 1971-1978 (Box 51)
  Includes reactor and two-component toroidal fusion test reactor studies, and statement on fusion energy
- Defense Intelligence Agency-United States Military Academy (DIA-USMA) co-operation, 1987 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  Letters, memoranda, minutes of meeting, notes, personnel record, and related materials
- "Science and Security: The Future of Arms Control," American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) colloquium, Washington, D.C., 1986 December 4-5 (Folder 52: 2)
  Agenda of meeting, articles by Sidney Drell, Thomas Johnson, and others, letters, list of participants, program, and remarks
- Articles by Thomas Johnson and others; course outline for fusion energy; reports on krypton fluoride laser, numerical simulation of laser fusion plasma; laser kinetics handbook; mirror systems, national security seminar, United States Military Academy; review of ICF program, project "Phobos," and related materials, 1971-1989
- Documentation for motion picture film, 1975 March (Folder 52: 3)
- Motion picture. A mathematical pools 24, 25, and 26 in the upper Mississippi and lower Illinois Rivers prepared for the Corps of Engineers by Yung H. Chen and Daryl B. Simons, Department of Civil Engineering, Colorado State University, 1975 March (Film-shelf shelf)
  One 16mm film reel
  - (1) Routing of 1965 flood in the upper Mississippi River
  - (2) Changes of bed elevation in the upper Mississippi River
  - (3) Changes of bed elevation in the upper Mississippi River (zero sediment inflow)
  - (4) Routing of 1965 flood in the lower Illinois River
  - (5) Dredging effects--Pool 25
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1987
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1987 (Reading room workstation)